<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="32"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[மைா் 04 Volume 04     இதழ 06 Issue 06     ஜூன 2021 JUNE 2021      விலை ரூ.30 Price  ₹.30
                                           ்
                                                               ்
       E-WASTE MANAGEMENT







      E-Waste: - Electronic waste or e-waste describes discarded electrical or electronic devices. Used electronics which are
      destined for reuse, resale, salvage, recycling, or disposal are also considered e-waste. Informal processing of e-waste in

      developing countries can lead to adverse human health effects and environmental pollution.






                               Resoled through                           Obsolete electronics
                                 remarketing                               enterthe recycle
                                  channels                                    process



         Old data is                                                                               Dismantle and
         destroyed                                                                                  Shredded to
        permanently                                                                                 optimal size

                       RESPONSIBLE                     Electronic        RESPONSIBLE
                             REUSE                    items are used         RECYCLE





       Device details noted
        and functionality                                                                       Seperated parts
            checked
                                                                                                  are sorted
                                       Working                     Combined and
                                      Electronics                new products are
                                      enter reuse                     created
                                       process






      Electronic scrap components, such as CPUs, contain potentially harmful materials such as lead, cadmium, beryllium, or
      brominated  flame  retardants.  Recycling  and  disposal  of  e-waste  may  involve  significant  risk  to  health  of  workers  and
      communities.










                            The Tamil Nadu Plastic Manufacturers' Association
                                                                                     gateway to the plastic industry]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                     2                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[CONTENTS






           Editorial                                                                                    04



           Newbies of Tapma family                                                                      06


                                                                                                        08



           World Environment Day                                                                        10


           Hatsun                                                                                       12



                                                                                                        16



           Single-use plastic                                                                           19


           Life saver sector                                                                            20



           Draft Plastic                                                                                22



           Bio-polymers                                                                                 24


           Snack Makers                                                                                 26



           Better Plastic                                                                               28



           The contents in POLYMER BUSINESS are sourced from various sources. The contents, views expressed in this Newsletter are not necessarily of that of TAPMA/
           POLYMER BUSINESS. Feedback and suggesssions are welcome and can be addressed to the Editor, POLYMER BUSINESS OFFICE. Publishing of all matters,
           articles in POLYMER BUSINESS are subject to approval by the Editor.
           Edited & Published by : S.Rakkappan on belhaf of TAPMA. C-1, First Floor, Rams Square, No.2, Valluvar Kottam High Road, Nungambakkam, Chennai - 600 034.












       POLYMER BUSINESS                                     3                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL






                                           Dearest Members,
                                           Shri S Balaji, our beloved EC Member remain a very nice person and his delightful
                                           behaving with everybody. Even the person may go away but his memories with us.
                                           Our heartfelt condolences to his family. May Shri S Balaji’s soul be at peace with
                                           the Almighty. His gentle soul will always be in our hearts. On behalf of TAPMA we
                                           have forwarded our heartfelt sympathies on the sad demise to his Family Members.
                                           THIRD WAVE OF CORONA IN INDIA
                                           The Government of India has recently issued a warning regarding the third wave
                                           of corona disease which  has been  continuously  spreading.  The Government
                                           has stated in unambiguous terms that the third wave of Corona will ensure if the
                                           Lockdown is not followed well. It is estimated that the third wave of corona is more
                                           dangerous than the first 2 waves. So far the third wave of Corona has arrived in the
                                           country and its number of patients has increased all over the country.
                                           PRECAUTIONS NEEDED TO STAY SAFE FROM COVID 19 THIRD WAVE
                                           •   Wash your hands thoroughly with soap.
                                           •     If you are going out, be sure to apply the mask and use a hand sanitizer
                                           •     Do not touch your face or mask frequently
                                           •   Make a distance of at least 2 yards from the infected
                                           •   When coughing cover the mouth with a handkerchief
                                           •   If your health is already weak then stay home
                                           •   Do not smoke and stay away from other lung weakening activities
                                           •   Do not go out of the house without any necessary work.
                                           In this situation it is important to stand UNITED AND HELP ONE ANOTHER in
                                           whatever way we can. Stay Safe and Stay Healthy.


                                               The below mail correspondences were Circulated to our Life Members.
                                             SL
                                             NO                   DESCRIPTION                  CIRCULATION DATE
                                                  Go Ms No. 364 dated 03 05 2021 – released by Revenue and Disas-
                                              1                                                REF:SR:AVR: 07 05 2021
                                                  ter Management (DMIV) stating the Guidelines and Relaxations etc…
                                                                                              Letter to Mr Satyendra Ku-
                                                  Submission of Suggestions – Draft Noticiation on Proposed Amend-  mar IAS – Secretary – Min-
                                              2
                                                  ments of Plastics Waste Management Rules 2016/2018  istry  of  Environment  on 10
         EDITORIAL ADVISORY BOARD                                                             05 2021
                           S.Rakkappan            Ministry of Commerce & Industry – Department of Commerce – D.O.
                                              3   NO. 13/9/SC-Logistics/2021 dated 7th April 2021 – Leads 2021 Sur-  20 05 2021
                      Editor and Publisher        vey on Logistics Sector.
                                TAPMA             Request for Relief – 6 months for 7 points - forwarded to State and
                                              4   Central Government – Ministers and Concerned Department Secre-  REF:SR:AVR:25 05 2021
                     EDITORIAL TEAM               taries . Circulated to Other Associations and Oil Refineries
                                                  Letter (1D) No. 89 dated 29 05 2021 from Thiru. Kumar IAS, Principal
                         N. Chandrasekar
                                              5   Secretary to Government – Covid 19 – Complete Lockdown extended  31 05 2021
                       G. Sampath Kumar           up to 07 06 2021 with relaxation details, Staff movement regarding
                          S. Prabhakaran          43rd Meeting of the GST Council New Delhi, 28th May, 2021- Press
                                S. Babu       6   Release GST rates on Goods and Services     31 05 2021
                         S.G. Mahadevan
                                                  Indian Center for Plastics in the Environment – Zoom Meeting-Sub-
                                              7                                               04 06 2021
                                                  ject–Plastics a boon or bane for environment
                  POLYMER BUSINESS
                                                  MSME – Incentives and Concessions viz Capital Subsidy GO 32 dat-
                                              8                                               04 06 2021
              C-1, First Floor, Rams Square       ed 01 06 2021
            No.2 Valluvar Kottam High Road        REVENUE AND DISASTER DM-IV 05 06 2021 Lockdown extension
                                              9                                               05 06 2021
         Nungambakkam, Chennai - 600 034          details
                       Ph : 044 2823 5893
         Email: polymer.business@gmail.com                                                       S Rakkappan
                                                                                                 President
                                                                                                 A Venkat Rao
                                                                                                 Secretary
       POLYMER BUSINESS                                     4                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                     5                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[Newbies of TAPMA family


















                                We Welcome You!







              S Rakkappan                                                                       A Venkat Rao
               President                                                                          Secretary













                                                                   Mr. Vikas Nahar
                                                                   Mr. Vijay Nahar
                                                                   Overseas Incorporation





                     Products:  Manufacturer, Importer, Exporter
                                    and Distributors of Electronic Toys
                                    and baby Products




                     Address:  New #43, 1 & II Floor,Rattan Bazaar,

                                   Park Town,Chennai - 600 003



                     Contact:  2535 2558 |98410 43465 | 98410 46578
                                   vikastoyhouse@gmail.com

                                   vijaynahar6@gmail.com
                                   www.toyhouse.co.in












       POLYMER BUSINESS                                     6                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                     7                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                     8                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                     9                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[World Environment Day



























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    10                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[World Environment Day

      Covid surge intensifies





      India’s plastic, biomedical




      waste problem






                 hile India was busy dealing with an            without any treatment with Bihar and Karnataka
                 unprecedented       healthcare     crisis,     faring the worst, it said.
      Wa  hazardous  mess  was  piling  in its
      backyard.                                                 “In 2019, India treated 88% of its biomedical waste,
                                                                down from 92.8% in 2017,” the report authored by
      The country produced biomedical waste to the tune         Kiran Pandey and Rajit Sengupta, said.
      of 2,03,000 kg per day as the coronavirus infection
      reached its peak and swamped hospitals, a report          Biomedical waste includes cultures, stocks of
      has revealed.                                             infectious agents, associated biologicals, human
                                                                blood and blood products, contaminated sharps,
      The report titled ‘State of India’s Environment 2021’,    amputated body parts and isolation waste.
      released by the Centre for Science and Environment,
      said the biomedical waste generated daily in May          Although it is a small proportion of the total waste
      this year was roughly 33% of India’s  non-Covid           generated (around 1%), it needs special handling
      biomedical waste.                                         due to its highly toxic contents that can pose a severe
                                                                threat to human health, the report said.
      Further, the biomedical waste generated in May was
      46% more than that in April when it had reached
      1.39 lakh kg per day. In March, the daily figure was
                                                                     FOR SALE
      75,000 kg.

      This is in line with data by the Central Pollution
      Control Board (CPCB) that said India 45,308 tonnes
      of Covid-19 biomedical waste between June 2020                         PET BOTTLES
      and 10 May 2021.
                                                                         BLOWING MACHINE
      The report found that Kerala, Gujarat, Maharashtra,
      Delhi and Karnataka contributed 50% of biomedical           MODEL: SA-PET 2000 X 2BJ
      waste generated in May. These states were hit
      particularly hard by the second wave of the Covid-19.
                                                                              MAKE: SIDEL
      Drawing a comparison, the report informed that the
      biomedical waste generated per day in 2017 was 5.59         In good working condition in
      lakh kg and the quantity of waste treated daily was
      519 kg. In 2019, 6.19 lakh kg biomedical waste was                          Chennai
      generated and 545 kg was treated daily.
                                                                  Contact: gre256@gmail.com
      India still disposes of 12% of its hospital waste

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    11                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Hatsun



























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    12                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Hatsun



























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    13                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Hatsun



























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    14                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Hatsun



























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    15                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                    16                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                    17                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                    18                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Single-use plastic
      India taking all steps to ensure it becomes


      free of single-use plastic by 2022: Javadekar



         ndia is taking all steps to ensure that the country    The campaign is being organised by the Federation of
         becomes free of single-use plastic by 2022 as          Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI),
         envisioned by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, Union      United  Nations  Environment  Programme  (UNEP)
      IEnvironment  Minister  Prakash  Javadekar  said  on      and GIZ (Deutsche Gesellschaft für Internationale
      Tuesday  while  launching  ‘Plastic  Hackathon  2021’     Zusammenarbeit),  a  German  organisation  working
      campaign.                                                 jointly with partners in India for sustainable economic,
                                                                                     ecological,    and      social
      Kick-starting  the  two-month                                                  development.
      long  awareness campaign
      on     single-use    plastics                                                  Gupta said intensive efforts
      (SUPs),  Javadekar,  in  an                                                    have been put in by the ministry
      audio message, said the                                                        to raise awareness and sensitise
      Environment    Ministry  has                                                   citizens on the environmental
      taken  several  steps  towards                                                 impact of SUP.
      eliminating single-use plastic
      from the country.                                                              “The government is providing
                                                                                     support to states for developing
      “Prime Minister Modi pledged                                                   adequate waste management
      to  make  the  country  free  of                                               infrastructure for solid and
      single  use  plastic.  We  took                                                plastic  waste   management
      several steps in that direction. The import of plastic    through  flagship  Swachh  Bharat  Mission  scheme,”  he
      waste has been banned. The states have been directed      said.
      to ensure no use of SUP. Several states have already
      stopped using SUP,” he said.                              Considering the adverse impacts of littered plastic
                                                                waste on both terrestrial and aquatic ecosystems, the
      “We  have  notified  plastic  waste  management  rules    prime minister gave a clarion call in 2019 to phase out
      under which plastic below 40 microns thickness cannot     single-use plastics by 2022.
      be used. We have also directed states to take action
      against companies producing plastic carry bags under      The  Ministry  of  Environment,  Forest  and  Climate
      40-micron thickness,” the minister added.                 Change had notified Plastic Waste Management Rules,
                                                                2016, for handling plastic waste in an environmentally
      Announcing the campaign, he said it will help finding     sound manner.
      suitable alternatives to SUP and identify new ways of
      plastic waste management.                                 Further,  the  ministry  has  issued  a  draft  notification
                                                                on  March  11,  2021  for  amending  the  Plastic  Waste
      “We  are  organising  a  Plastic  Hackathon  2021.  It  will   Management  Rules,  2016,  with  respect  to  prohibiting
      deliberate on plastic waste management, its collection    identified SUP items following a phase-out schedule in
      and what new products can be made out of it. Suitable     2022.
      alternative to SUP will also be discussed in this
      hackathon.  Essay  competitions  will  be  organised  for   Littered plastic waste on land is recognised as a major
      school kids. Till the time online classes are going on for   source of marine plastic litter. Plastic waste management
      schools and colleges, such activities will be enjoyed by   on land will significantly contribute to the reduction in
      students and they can participate with full enthusiasm,”   the generation of marine plastic litter, ministry sources
      Javadekar said.                                           said.

      Before  the  minister’s  message,  a  virtual  event  was   FICCI Secretary General Dilip Chenoy said the campaign
      organised  by  FICCI  where  Environment  Secretary  R    is being launched on the auspicious occasion of World
      P Gupta said the campaign is an effort to raise the       Oceans Day and that FICCI will put its best efforts in
      capacity of various stakeholders with respect to plastic   making it a success.
      pollution.
                                                                The  United  Nations  has  designated  June  8  as  World
      “It will be a two-month long campaign with a series of    Oceans Day.
      events on reducing plastic waste generation, recognising
      the need of effective plastic waste management,           The UNEP and GIZ India are the knowledge partners
      increasing the awareness of suitable alternatives,        and FICCI is the industry partner for the campaign.
      sustainable consumption and production and extended
      producer responsibility (EPR),” Gupta said.


       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    19                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[life saver sector

      PLASTICS – A LIFE SAVER SECTOR- INNOVATED

      BY HUMAN BEING FOR HUMAN LIFE


            lastics - a life saver sector e.g. Operation        New plastic technologies are allowing medical
            theatres    75%    equipments’      products        inventors and manufacturing engineers to
     Pinvented is Plastics it is one of the most                develop new medical devices. Because of the
      advanced  material  humanity  ever  created               ability to design and manufacture components
      contributing to longer healthier lives of public          from the tiniest and intricate molds, plastics
      at large is a gift & great resource which saves           are now being used in surgical devices
      countless lives, prevents diseases at large. Acts         and  procedures,  and  products  like  modern
      like  mother  does  work  every  day  but  it  is  in     pacemakers,  stents,  or  joint  replacement
      back stage.                                               devices.

      Plastics as a material is very versatile and has          Plastics have helped contribute to a reduction
      saved millions of lives during this ongoing               in medical costs, for the medical providers –
      Covid pandemic. Unfortunately, the perception             and translated to consumer costs. For example,
      of plastics continues to remain negative which            cost savings has come from the use of smaller,
      in itself is a paradox. We need to correct the            lightweight and portable medical devices used
      perception of plastics amongst civil society and          in in-home treatments (such as kidney dialysis
      governments by highlighting the                                         machines, bathtub chairseat lifts,
      potential of Plastics in healthcare                                     or even simple bed pans).
      and medicine.
                                                                              Plastic components have helped
      Modern healthcare would not be                                          healthcare patients live healthier
      possible without the use of plastic                                     and happier lives, while at the sea
      materials. From the casing of an                                        time passing the savings onto the
      open MRI machine to the smallest                                        healthcare device manufacturers
      tubing, plastics have made health                                       and healthcare providers. As
      care simpler and less painful.                                          healthcare continues to improve,
      Things we take for granted such as                                      so will the use and effectiveness
      disposable syringes, intravenous                                        of plastic components. Much
      blood bags and heart valves are                                         needed Ventilators connectivity
      all made of plastic.                                                    to body interface is through
                                                                plastics,  Oxygen      Concentrator     interface.
      Patients  have  directly  benefitted  from  plastic       List is fairly long & new inventions are with
      within  medical  devices.  To  help  combat  the          it. Protecting our Front line Heroes Doctors
      growing concern of hospital-borne infections,             Nurses  Safai  worker  drivers  etc  in  the  most
      high tech polymers and “antimicrobial plastic”            dangerous job in the world .
      have been created and used in devices that
      reduce the risk of infection to patients. These           During Covid Pandemic, Plastics has played
      plastics repel or even kill most bacteria, even           a  crucial  role  and  has  saved  lives  of  millions
      on high-touch surfaces, preventing infections.            of people. It would have not been possible
      Interestingly,  antimicrobial  plastics  have  an         to  fight  Covid  without  the  mass  availability
      extremely high effectiveness of killing bacteria          of  Personal  Protective  Equipment  kits,  face
      even when surfaces aren’t regularly cleaned.              mask,  face  shields,  surgical  gowns,  goggles,
                                                                disposable caps, shoe covers, gloves, Oxygen
      Just from the use of safety measures inherent             Concentrators, Vaccine bottle Closure, Vaccine
      to or designed into plastic components, plastic           Syringes,  Test  Kits  RTPCR  Swab,  Plastic
      has  had  a  significant  impact  on  increased           Spirometer Humidifier breathing filters etc.
      safety  of  patients.  For  example,  virtually  all
      pharmaceutical  packaging  has  tamper-proof              Just from the use of safety measures inherent
      measures such as blister packs and childproof             to or designed into plastic components, plastic
      caps.                                                     has  had  a  significant  impact  on  increased
                                                                safety of patients.

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    20                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[life saver sector
































      The  ability  to  create  devices  where  it  wasn’t      life of these number of patients per year. In the
      previously possible. New plastic technologies             current COVID situation plastics has served as
      such as 3D printing is                                                        a MOTHER for saving life of
      allowing medical inventors                                                    people. 3rd Wave of COVID
      and manufacturing engineers                                                   feared on children. Plastic
      to  develop  new  medical                                                     see    through     Incubators
      devices.                                                                      for   new     born    children
                                                                                    gives warmth to children &
      Plastics     for    biomedical                                                protects them against virus.
      applications     have     many
      desirable           properties,                                               PLASTIC DRESS – KIT
      including low cost, ease of processing, and
      [ability] to be sterilized easily.                        This equipment’s made of Plastics are helping
                                                                doctors in saving precious lives during Covid.
      Some of the key examples of plastics in                   Use of 3D printing has led to stronger & safer
      healthcare are as follows: -                              products leading to new form of treatment
                                                                to patients. Plastics has truly emerged as
      •  Cardiac Balloon Catheter & Stent used                  strongest Front Line Warrior.
          during Angioplasty
                                                                Plastics is one of the most advanced and useful
      •  Urinal Bed Pan we put                                  material humanity has ever invented. Its wide

      •  Dicing table on X Ray                                  use in pharma and medicine  has contributed
                                                                towards healthier and longer life span of people.
      •  Operation theatre lights                               It’s a gift and resource for the mankind as its
                                                                prevents diseases and saves countless lives.
      •  Dialysis unit

      •  PC Container for collection of sample
      •  Diabetes  Embedded  Patches  delivering
          insulin to patient without injection

      •  IV bags                                                                                      Arvind M. Mehta
                                                                                      Chairman -Governing Council AIPMA
      A staggering number of Dialysis patients cured                                    Past President – AIPMA & Plastindia
      per year is 4 Crore and Diabetes patients is 10                                                     Foundation
      Crore, who are treated with the equipments
      made of plastics. Plastics serves to save the

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    21                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Draft Plastic

      Draft plastic waste rules:



      Why multi-layered plastic



      needs to be phased out





              he implementation of plastic waste                (SUP), which is a part of the draft notification.
              management rules in India has been off-           But the illusion created by the plastic industry-
              track since 1999, mainly due to intense           run associations — that MLPs are not SUPs —
      Tlobbying by associations and bodies                      seems to have outmanoeuvred the authorities.
      formed and funded by the plastic industry. One
      such issue that has been delayed time and again           MLP, according to 2016 rules, is defined as:
      is phasing out of multi-layered plastics (MLP)            Any material used or to be used for packaging
      used for packaging by fast-moving consumer                and  having  at  least  one  layer  of  plastic  as
      goods (FMCG) companies.                                   the main ingredient in combination with one
      The  idea  of  phasing  out  MLPs  was  first             or more layers  of  material  such  as paper,
      introduced in the draft Plastic (Manufacture,             paperboard, polymeric material, metalised
      Usage  and  Waste  Management)  Rules,  2009,             layers or aluminium foil, either in the form of
      wherein the clause 5(f) spoke about restricting           laminate or co-extruded structure.
      the use of MLPs that fall under non-recyclable                           It is a well-known fact that MLPs
      plastic.                                                                 are non-recyclable and most
      The notified rules of Plastic Waste                                      urban local bodies pay huge
      (Management and Handling)                                                amounts of money to transport
      Rules, 2011, deleted the clause in                                       these low-value materials to
      entirety. A gradual phase out of                                         waste-to-energy and cement
      MLPs was re-attempted through                                            plants for co-processing, where
      the Plastic  Waste Management                                            they are burnt under the disguise
      Rules,  2016,  wherein  clause                                           of “energy recovery”.
      9(3)  advocated  phasing  out  all                                       Energy  recovery  is  a  term
      multi-layered plastics used for                                          introduced      by     the     2018
      packaging in two years.                                                  amendment          rules,    which

      This    was     again     rendered                                       conveniently bypassed the main
      toothless by the Plastic Waste                                           agenda  of  phasing  MLPs  out
      Amendment Rules, 2018, by adding the phrases              within a stipulated time. MLPs, therefore, need
      “non-energy recoverable” and “alternate use”              to be re-defined and brought under the ambit
      alongside “non-recyclable”.                               of single-use plastic.
      Nearly 12 years later, the agenda of restricting          As a matter of fact, most plastic waste reaches
      the use of MLPs is off the charts. The draft              the recycling stage only because of foot-soldiers
      Plastic Waste Management Rules, 2021, issued              like waste-pickers. Interestingly, waste-pickers
      by the Union Ministry of Environment, Forests             are defined in the Plastic Waste Management
      and  Climate  Change  (MoEFCC)  on  March  11,            Rules, 2016; but they have not been identified
      have failed to address the elephant in the room.          or acknowledged as an association or body that
                                                                ensures a say in the value chain as opposed to
      A report by Delhi-based Centre for Science                an  individual  waste-picker  who  is  vulnerable
      and Environment titled Managing plastic waste             and has almost no to limited bargaining power
      in India- Challenges and Agenda had strongly              and selling options.
      advocated  for  defining  single-use  plastic

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    22                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Draft Plastic
































                                                                Even the Union Ministry of Housing and Urban
                                                                Affairs (MoHUA) thanked the informal sector in
                                                                its SBM Plastic Waste Book published in March
                                                                2019. Unfortunately, the informal sector is not
                                                                defined  in  any  plastic  waste  rules  that  have
                                                                been notified in the country.

                                                                There  is  a  need  to  define  and  acknowledge
                                                                the contribution of the informal sector, which
                                                                practically feeds the formal plastic recyclers
                                                                who rely heavily on mechanical recycling.
                                                                It  is  the  most  sustainable  known  form  of
                                                                plastic  recycling;  after  2018  amendments
                                                                in  the  Plastic  Waste  Management  Rules,
                                                                however, a considerable fraction is routed for
                                                                co-processing,  incineration and unsustainable
                                                                burning in waste-to-energy plants and is
                                                                conveniently termed as recycling.

                                                                It needs to be clearly mentioned that recycling
                                                                is different from energy recovery (incineration,
                                                                co-processing and waste-to-energy) and
                                                                alternate  use  (road-making),  with  recycling
                                                                being  the  best  option.  The  new  definition  of
                                                                waste processing should not include plastic
                                                                recycling.
















       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    23                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Bio-polymers


































                                                           Smart solution



                                                           for solving the



                                                           plastic waste




                                                           problem







































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    24                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Bio-polymers


             he hazards of plastic waste are well known         “The usual methods of recycling cannot be qualified
             across the globe. In fact, India alone produces    as a completely green solution. For example, there is a
      T9.46 million tonnes of plastic waste every year,         limit to recycling paper and every kg of paper uses 70
      of which 40% remains uncollected. And 43% is used         litres of water to recycle, which is counterproductive,”
      for packaging, most of it single-use.                     he says.

      About 60% of this has ended up in landfills or in the     “Similarly, the process of recycling aluminum and
      natural environment. Notably, the current industry        recyclable plastic has high upfront capital costs
      practice to make plastic sustainable is to make it        and these processes themselves are unhygienic and
      recyclable.                                               unsafe. Even the recycled products are not of very
                                                                high quality.”
      The real green and sustainable solution for the
      industry is to take a leap from recyclable plastic and    According to him, the major advantage of Dr Bio
      move  towards  bio-compostable plastic  which  will       is that the bio-based polymers replace fossil carbon
      dissolve in the soil to make a strong positive impact     in the production process with renewable carbon
      on plastic waste management as well as reduce plastic     from biomass. This is indispensable for a sustainable,
      in the landfills, says Mukul Sareen, director, business   climate-friendly plastics industry. The second
      development, Hi-Tech International.                       advantage is that they are biodegradable (depending
                                                                on the environment) and can therefore be a solution
      Hi-Tech International is said to be the first company     for plastics that cannot be collected. This results in
      in the country to manufacture a plant-based               elimination of micro plastics from our environment.
      biopolymer—Dr Bio —which can be used to replace
      single-use and multi-use plastic products such as         The company now plans to address the needs of the
      bottles, straws, cups, disposable cutlery, polybags, etc.,   packaging industry and its clients with this sustainable
      with bio-compostable plastic. Dr Bio is the only Indian   solution for their single use and multi-use plastic
      biopolymer to have been approved by the Institute of      needs. “We are in advanced stages of negotiation with
      Petrochemicals Technology (formerly known as—             many Indian and multinational companies across
      Central Institute of  Petrochemicals  Engineering  &      sectors such as FMCG, consumables and cosmetics.
      Technology)—thus uniquely positioning Hi-Tech
      International to drive the plastic industry towards       At the same time, our international partners located
      sustainable bio-compostable plastic.                      in 45 countries have seen great potential and are
                                                                willing to invest in India with us for this technology
      “Dr Bio is India’s only compostable polymer, which        and many overseas organisations have already
      means the plastic made from this polymer will             adopted  this  biopolymer  to  replace  their  current
      disintegrate after 12-14 weeks and will completely        plastic needs,” he adds. “The idea is to collaborate
      biodegrade after six months,” says Sareen. “That means    closely with corporate, government, academia and
      that the bioplastic material will be converted to CO2     NGOs to increase the usage of this sustainable bio-
      and the remaining share is converted into water and       polymer in lieu of conventional plastic. The vision
      biomass, which no longer contains any plastic waste.      is to create a strong positive impact on landfills and
      No heavy metal contents and no harmful substances         oceans in terms of reduction of plastic waste,” says
      should be left behind.”                                   Sareen.

      According  to  Sareen, this innovation  is  slated  to
      transform the plastic waste management industry.
      The company has set up a 200,000 sq ft plant in
      Ludhiana for  production of this  bio-polymer and
      plans to invest Rs 100 crore over a period of 2-3 years
      in the project.



       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    25                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Snack Makers












































      Snack makers to resize packs to


      meet Maharashtra’s plastic norms




             elow image- take only text and design it in your   India, ITC and Cavinkare.
             way. Just like how this is, in between add it as
      Bfacts                                                    PepsiCo India is resizing packs of its bestselling Lay’s
                                                                and Kurkure as it ramps up sustainable packaging
       One always wonders why 100gm of branded potato           solutions amid growing concerns over plastic depleting
       chips or any other snack comes in a packet that could    the environment, said a company spokesperson. The
       easily  contain  five  times  the  quantity.  Well,  snack   fastest selling units of Lay’s are the Rs5 and Rs10 packs
       manufacturers are now considering reducing packet        of American cream onion and magic masala flavours,
       sizes to bring down plastic use. The plan is in keeping   and of Kurkure are similar packs of the masala munch
       with the Maharashtra government’s anti-plastic steps,    flavour.
       which includes attempts to clamp down on multi-
       layer packaging for fast moving consumer goods           ITC,  which  makes  Bingo  and  Mad  Angles,  too  is
       (FMCG).                                                  looking for a solution. “Over the next decade, ITC will
                                                                deploy superior solutions so that 100% of its product
       Though plastic used at the manufacturing stage is        packaging will be reusable, recyclable or compostable.
       exempt from the plastic ban that has been imposed        Already, over 99% of solid waste generated in ITC’s
       in the state, the government told FMCG companies         factories is recycled,” said a spokesperson.
       last month to come up with solutions for package
       recycling and reuse. Among the companies that have       Then,  the  Chennai-based  Cavinkare  is  looking  to
       shown an intention to follow the order are PepsiCo       “optimise” its raw material intake of plastic for its
                                                                Garden snacks brand. The company is also working

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    26                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Snack Makers


























































      on a buyback process specific to Maharashtra, a
      spokesperson told TOI.  Some FMCG companies,
      including  Coca  Cola  and  Bisleri,  are offering a
      buyback price of Rs 15 for a kg of PET bottles and Rs
      5 for a kg of shrink wraps.

      FMCG companies are also looking for alternatives to
      PET bottles, though the state has allowed their use
      provided there is a buyback mechanism. PepsiCo is
      looking to introduce non-returnable glass packaging
      for its beverage brands. It launched Pepsi Black in this
      format. The firm is also attempting to recycle plastic
      films to convert into fuel. A pilot has been initiated at
      the company’s Pune plant. “We are yet to figure out
      how and where the fuel will be utilized. But we are       solutions will come at a cost and the firms will have
      making progress,” said a spokesperson.                    to ensure that margins are such that their business
                                                                remains sustainable and viable.
      Even as companies look to reduce plastic  use, the


       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    27                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Better Plastic






























             Better Plastic™ Converting



                            Plastic Waste into



                     High-Quality Granules













              he  climate  crisis  has  forced  mankind         into  plastic  flakes  or  pellets  that  can  be
              to reassess its collective priorities             remolded into new products. Global brands are
              and  rethink  everything  from  power             increasingly using these recycled plastics over
      Tgeneration and storage, to farming                       virgin plastics in their products and packaging.
      methods and transportation. The relationship              Better  Plastic™  is  one such  product,  created
      with  plastic  has  also  been  examined;  the            by Indian company Banyan, using proprietary
      ubiquitous and once revolutionary material                plastic recycling technology.
      is  used  for  everything  from  food  and  drinks
      containers, cosmetics bottles, and toys, to car           Banyan’s Better Plastic
      parts and consumer electronics.                           India has the second-largest population in

      Plastic is useful, but the raw materials for many         the world but has one of the lowest rates of
      of them are fossil fuels, a finite resource. Once         plastic  consumption  in  the  world  –  just  11  kg
      it has served its useful purpose, the plastic is          per person annually, compared to around 109
      often simply discarded. This plastic waste can            kg per person in America. Nonetheless, plastic
      persist in the environment for thousands of               waste in the country is a growing concern.
      years, breaking down into smaller components              To tackle the problem, Banyan, one of India’s
      over time, which find their way into the water            first  vertically  integrated  plastic  recycling
      cycle and the food chain.                                 companies, is using its proprietary plastic

      Plastic waste is increasingly being recycled              cleaning technology to convert discarded
                                                                plastic waste into Better Plastic™, a high-

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    28                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Better Plastic





















      quality recycled granule that is equivalent in           collection systems can be improved, and more
      quality and performance to virgin plastic. This          plastics redesigned or replaced, recovered, and
      is  a  first  in  India’s  highly  informal,  low-tech   recycled.
      industry, state the company.
                                                               Banyan  has  taken  an  important  first  step
      Banyan’s       cleaning      technology        uses      in  tackling  plastic  waste  in  India;  their  data
      environmentally      friendly   detergents     and       intelligence  platform  is  one  of  the  first  to
      solvents to remove ink, coatings,                                             use  mobile,  cloud,  and
      and other contaminants from                                                   the   Internet    of   Things
      post-consumer plastics such as                                                (IoT)  to  link  thousands  of
      shampoo and cosmetic bottles,                                                 informal recyclers into their
      and    post-industrial    plastics                                            supply chain to recover
      such as car parts or paint cans.                                              post-consumer and post-
                                                                                    industrial plastic waste.
      The     scientifically   rigorous
      process       of     segregation,                                             The platform also enables
      washing,       and      extrusion                                             the companies to help
      helps to identify resins with                                                 cities  manage  their  waste
      a high degree of accuracy                                                     effectively by helping them
      while also preventing cross-                                                  understand and improve
      contamination  and  eliminating                                               waste  flow  through  their
      product       and      packaging                                              cities  to  make  it  more
      contamination.                                                                economical,  efficient,  and
                                                                                    effective.
      The result is consistently high-
      quality,  near  virgin-quality  recycled  granules.      Banyan has collaborated with global brands to
      Banyan says the addition of performance                  develop a circular economy leadership. It has
      polymers  allows  it  to  meet  the  stringent           pioneered closed-loop recycling initiatives with
      thermal and mechanical properties required of            Tata  Motors,  India’s  leading  car  company,  to
      high-performance automotive and consumer                 make new bumpers from old ones, and with a
      products.                                                global cosmetic company L’Oréal to make new
                                                               bottles from discarded ones. Banyan hopes
      The recycled resins can be used in consumer              its recycling initiatives can be extended to
      packaging,  car  components,  furniture,  and            industries across the country.
      consumer electronics, with Banyan offering
      standard as well as custom-graded recycled
      compounds.

      Links in the Chain
      Many of us try to reuse or recycle our plastics but
      plastic waste issues remain a global problem.
      To  make  improvements,  the  whole  plastics
      value chain must be considered so that waste

       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    29                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Polymer Business











                                   Advertisement Tariff







                                                                                           TOTAL AMOUNT
                 COLOR AD              RATE PER ISSUE                GST 5%
                                                                                           -SINGLE ISSUE
                PLACEMENT                     (₹)                       (₹)
                                                                                                  (₹)
          Front Cover                       18000/-                    900/-                   18900/-
          Front Inner Cover                 12000/-                    600/-                   12600/-

          Inside Full Page                  6000/-                     300/-                    6300/-
          Back Inner Cover                  10000/-                    500/-                   10500/-

          Back Cover                        15000/-                    750/-                   15750/-




         Creative/Advertisement Size - W 19 x H 26 cms
         Design/Artwork - High resolution PDF / JPEG / Photoshop with 300 DPI Resolution
         BANK DETAILS:
         Account Name : The Tamilnadu Plastics Manufacturers' Association
         Account No : 10397604483
         State Bank of India , Siruthozhil Branch, Chetpet, Chennai
         IFS CODE : SBIN0006616



         Note:-
         Advertisement charges have to be paid in ADVANCE by NEFT/RTGS
         Demand Draft/Cheque in favour of : TAPMA
         Advertisement Material must reach us on or before 25th of every month for the following
         month.
         TAPMA reserves the right to accept any advertisement



         Polymer Business
         The Tamilnadu Plastics Mfrs.' Association (TAPMA),
         C-1, 1st Floor, "Rams Square",
         2, Valluvar Kottam High Road,
         Nungambakkam, Chennai - 600 034
         Phone: 044-28235893
         Mobile: 9543446667





       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    30                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[POLYMER BUSINESS                                    31                                            JUNE 2021]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[nd
       RNI NO. : TNBIL/2018/76005 | Postal Reg. No. : TN/CH/(C)/561/2019-2021 | Date of Publication : 2 Week of Every Month
                                   Posted at Patrika Chennel, Egmore RMS/1 on 17-06-2021

























































































       POLYMER BUSINESS                                    32                                            JUNE 2021]]></page></pages></Search>